teachworks.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy | Teachworks

Teachworks (collectively, "Teachworks", "we", "us", or "our") is committed to protecting your privacy online. Our pledge is to safeguard any information we collect associated with you and your name, and will make every reasonable effort to use this information only as you request.

This Privacy Policy applies to the website teachworks.com (the "Site", or "Service"). This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, share and secure the personal information you provide, as well as the information about our customers' customers or end users that we process on behalf of our customers. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, correction and deletion of your personal information.

### 1\. How We Collect Your Information

#### Information that you provide to us about yourself

In connection with accessing or using our Service, we may collect information from you which can be used to identify you ("Personal Information"), such as your name, business name and address, email address, phone, and other information about your business. Some of this information is required to use the Service.

We collect information when you register or open an account, sign in, pay a bill, purchase a Service, call us for support, or give us feedback.

#### Information you provide to us about your customers, employees, and end users

For the provision of our Service to you, you provide us with information which may identify your customers, employees, or end users.

When you provide personal information about your customers, employees, or end users we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided.

#### Information collected automatically

We use the electronic records to compile statistics about how collectively our visitors interact with our Web site. These statistics contain no personal information and are only used by the Teachworks technical support staff.

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Even without cookies, you can access certain public-facing pages of our site. However, session cookies are required to login to your account.

### 2\. How We Use Your Information

Teachworks will not sell, exchange, or give your information collected online to a third party. 

To the extent EU data protection law applies to our processing of information about you, we act as the "data controller". To the extent EU data protection law applies to our processing of your customer or end user data, you serve as the "data controller" or "data processor" and we serve as the "data processor" or "data sub-processor".

#### To Provide the Service:

We use your information to identify you, process your payments, provide you with technical support and assistance; and communicate with you about the Services via email. For example we will contact you to notify you of any issues with the Services or any suspicious activity in your account. The legal basis for these uses in the performance of the contract with you.

#### To Optimize or Improve the Service:

We use your information to authenticate you, prevent fraud and abuse of our Services, get feedback, and perform research. The legal basis for these uses is our legitimate interest in the improvement and optimization of our service offerings and in ensuring the security of our services and we apply appropriate safeguards to protect your information.

### 3\. How We Share Your Information 

We share information with service providers, as required by law, and in connection with the protection and enforcement of our legal and contractual rights.

#### With Service Providers:

We may share some of your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities. This includes: payment processing, sending emails, sending text messages, providing customer service, sending marketing communications (this does not include information about your customers), conducting research and analysis and providing cloud computing infrastructure. The legal basis for sharing this information is our legitimate interest in providing our Services efficiently and we implement measure to safeguard your information.

#### With Public Authorities or Law Enforcement:

In certain situations, Teachworks may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your personal information as required by law (such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process), when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, to protect your safety or the safety of others, to investigate fraud, to respond to a government request, if we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, or if we are involved in a bankruptcy or liquidation proceeding. The legal basis for this is our legitimate interest in protecting our legal rights and those of others, compliance with legal obligations and our legitimate interest in fulfilling legal obligations imposed by legal authorities outside of the EU.

### 4\. Rights & Choices With Respect to Your Information

You can view and edit information that identifies you online through your Teachworks account. You have a choice about the use of information that identifies you, marketing communications you receive from us, and in some cases our use of cookies. 

#### Managing Marketing Communications From Us

We do not wish to send you any unwanted email, and have tried to make it easy for you to unsubscribe from any service you have requested. If you are receiving email announcements of our new features and updates, and wish to stop receiving them, you can click the "Unsubscribe" link in the footer of the e-mail.

#### Updating Your Personal Information

In connection with your right to manage your Personal Information that you provide to us, you may access, update, change, correct or request deletion of your information either through the Service or through our customer support.

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, obtain a copy of or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or by contacting us at the contact information below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

Teachworks acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Teachworks has no direct relationship with your customers or end users whose personal data it processes. An individual that is a customer, employee or end user of a Teachworks client who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the Teachworks client (the data controller) with whom they have a relationship. If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

### 5\. Data retention

We may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

### 6\. Security

We provide reasonable and appropriate security measures in connection with securing Personal Information we collect. For example, we:

  * Constantly work to update our security practices to implement accepted best methods to protect your Personal Information, and review our security procedures carefully. 
  * We use encryption for all connections to the Site for transmitting information
  * Train our staff and require them to safeguard your data.
  * Do not store any payment card data on our servers.

### 7\. International Data Transfers 

If you are using the Service from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information to the United States where our servers are located. Our collection, storage and use of your Personal Data will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy. The Site's servers are hosted by a web services provider that is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. You can find more information about their compliance here: [AWS EU-US Privacy Shield](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/eu-us-privacy-shield-faq/)

### 8\. Changes to Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. 

### 9\. How to Contact Us

If you have concerns about your privacy with the Teachworks Web site, please tell us by submitting an email to support at teachworks dot com. 

_Last Updated: May 25, 2018_
